In this clip we'll be evaluating the clients hair texture and type.
That's totally important for the end result.
Often times the client will come in and they'll be requesting a particular hair cut or a particular hairstyle and their hair texture just won't work for that.
The best way to do that is to actually get your hands into the hair and feel what's going on.
When your hands are in there you can feel the texture, the density.
At this time, at this time it's also a good opportunity to analyze if there are any colics in the particular clients hair.
A colic is a growth pattern where the hair swirls in a particular direction.
It's very important to be aware of that before you begin the cut.
Typically, in those areas, if the cut is taken too short, the hair is going to stick straight out.
On our particular clients hair today, we can see that his growth pattern is such that it wants to stick straight out.
His hair is relatively fine but it's very thick and has that very straight direction to it so there's absolutely no bend and because of that, he basically has two choices.
He either needs to grow his hair out a little bit longer so that the weight will actually keep this growth pattern in check and keep the hair down or he needs to take it considerably shorter so that as the hair pokes out, which it's going to do, it's doing so in a shape that's acceptable,